

## Leon Ingelse

#### **Contact**

■ leoningelse@gmail.com

leoningel.github.io

github.com/Leoningel

Leon Ingelse

□ +31645341995

## Languages

Dutch	Native
English	C2
Spanish	C1
Portuguese	B2

# Computer skills

Python	4.5 yrs.
git	4.5 yrs.
SQL	3.5 yrs.
R	2 yrs.
F#	1.5 yrs.
Java	0.5 yrs.

## **Biography**

As a mathematician, I am analytical, critical, and a natural problem-solver. As an Al researcher, I have developed various technical skills and gained extensive experience in both independent work and group projects. Although I have a technical background, my social and communicative skills will surprise you. My curiosity for the unknown has taken me around the world and allowed me to engage with different cultures and diverse worldviews.

I speak 4 languages - of which 3 at a professional level. My passions are technological innovation, writing, social justice, exercising and engaging in public discourse. I am independent, sociable, reliable, resourceful, positive, creative and critical. I am also a quick learner and a transparent communicator. Feel free to reach out for a chat!

## Work experience

Researcher & Writer

06/2024 - Ongoing

Dots & Lines | Remote | Part-time freelancer

Data Analyst

03/2024 - 10/2024

Onja | Toamasina (Madagascar) - Remote

Research Assistant

02/2021 - 10/2023

<u>LASIGE</u> | Lisbon | Remote

Funded by FCT – Supervised by Prof. Fonseca

Main achievements: See publications and Genetic Engine

Research Journalist

05/2023 - 11/2023

Global Voices | Remote

Works: Al usage by Dutch government - Colonialism in Portugal

Software Engineer and Data Scientist

02/2019 - 08/2020

Impact Institute | Amsterdam

Research & Development team. Main achievement: Global Impact Database.

High School Tutor

09/2014 - 01/2018

OVER huiswerkbegeleiding | Amsterdam

Side Jobs

Besides the above, I have done numerous side jobs, e.g., sales agent, receptionist, cleaner, cook, bartender, dish washer, ice cream seller, grape picker, and cashier, amongst others.

### **Education**

Data Science (M.Sc.) | GPA: 18 (/20)

09/2020 - 09/2022

University of Lisbon

Al • ML • Explainable Al • Genetic Programming • Feature Learning • Databases Thesis: "Optimisation of Feature Learning through Grammar-Guided GP".

Mathematics (B.Sc.) | GPA: 7.06 (/10)

09/2014 - 01/2019

University of Amsterdam

Algebra • Real analysis • Number theory • Topology • Statistics

Thesis: "p-Adic numbers and the local-global principle".

International Development (Minor)

09/2018 - 01/2019

University of Amsterdam

Spanish (Minor)

09/2016 - 12/2016

Pontificia Católica Universidad de Chile

#### Selected publications (see all)

Ingelse, Leon, et al. Comparing Individual Representations in Grammar-Guided Genetic Programming for Glucose Prediction in People with Diabetes. GECCO workshop (2023).

Ingelse, Leon, and Fonseca, Alcides, (2023). *Domain-Aware Feature Learning with Grammar-Guided Genetic Programming*. EuroGP 2023 Proceedings. Springer Nature.

Ingelse, Leon, et al. (2022). Personalised Gait Recognition for People with Neurological Conditions. Sensors 22.11 (2022): 3980.

#### **Projects**

Writer

09/2023 - Ongoing

Besides my research, I write opinion pieces, promotional texts for <u>LRC</u> and poetry, and I have written for the newsletter of <u>Lumiera</u> and  $\overline{\text{VvdO}}$ .

**Trumpet Player** 

Candy Flip | Lisbon

Body Painter

Risquinhos de Leon | Lisbon

Boulder Gym | Co-founder & Manager

Floresta de Baobás | Lisbon

Student Ambassador | Leader Creative Committee

International office University of Amsterdam

09/2022 - Ongoing

06/2023 - Ongoing

06/2023 - 02/2024

02/2017 - 08/2017

#### Volunteering

Distributor

Fruta Feia | Lisbon

Cook

Zona Franca nos Anjos | Lisbon

Coordinator

Buurtbuik West | Amsterdam

Football trainer

Escuela de Fútbol Clotario Blest | Santiago de Chile

09/2023 - Ongoing

09/2023 - 02/2024

10/2019 - 09/2020

09/2016 - 12/2016